Brave Exkaiser
勇 者 エクスカイザ- 용자 엑스카이저
Over a million of them shine with a blue light
靑く輝く 幾千万の 푸르게 빛나는 몇천만개의
The shards of love have scattered
愛のかけらが ちりばめられた 사랑의 조각들이 흩어져 있어
It's brewing in this world
この 地球(ほし)の中 蠢く 이 지구 안에 휘몰아치는
A storm that you'll confront
嵐に向かう 폭풍우로 달려가는
And because I believe in you
君を信じたから 너를 믿으니까
I'm not afraid of anything
何も恐れないさ 아무것도 두렵지 않아
GO WITH ME Exkaiser
GO WITH ME エクスカイザ-！ GO WITH ME 엑스카이저!
Courage and friendship
勇氣と友情！ 용기와 우정!
That moment when we join our strength GATHER WAY
力 あわせた その 時 GATHER AWAY 힘을 합치는 그순간 GATHER AWAY
GO WITH ME Exkaiser
GO WITH ME エクスカイザ-！ GO WITH ME 엑스카이저!
I'd almost forgotten it
忘れかけていた！ 잊고 있었던
The fiery burning and important PASSIONATE feeling in my heart
熱く 燃える 大切な PASSIONATE この 胸に 뜨겁게 불타는 소중한 PASSIONATE내 가슴에!
The mysterious and vast universe.
신비하고 광대한 우주 성우:山寺宏一야마데라 코이치
In this universe exists the evil life forms, the space pirates Geisters
그 안에 악의 에너지 생명체
In pursuit was Exkaiser of the cosmic police, who possessed the car of the Hoshikawa family.
그것을 추적하던 우주경찰 엑스카이저는 호시카와家의 자동차로 몸을 삼는다
And by transforming into the robot form of Exkaiser, he saved Kouta.
변형로봇 엑스카이저가 되어 코우타를 구해낸다
This is the story of Brave Exkaiser and his friends, who fight against evil all around the universe.
이것은 우주에 퍼지고 있는 악과 싸우는
Save the Linear Motor Car!
第２話　リニア.モ-タ-カ-を助けて 第２話 리니아 모타카를 구해줘! 放映日 1990/2/10
Meanwhile, unlike Kyoto which is still cold, on the southern area of Okinawa, cherry blossoms have already opened.
한편 시기적으로 추위가 가시지 않은 쿄토와는 달리 오키나와 남부에서는 한발 앞서 벚꽃이 피었다는..
Under high atmospheric pressure, Hokkaido will have a clear weather today, but tomorrow's weather will be affected by...
오늘 홋카이도는 고기압에 따라 하루종일 맑겠습니다 하지만 내일 아침은 대륙의...
That's it! Destroy it some more!
잘한다 잘해! 더 부수라구!
Blow it up!
폭발시켜 버려!
Oh! Let it burn!
이젠 좀이 쑤셔 죽겠다구!
I have orders from lord Dino Geist.
다이노 가이스터님으로부터 지시다
Has he chosen a target?
타겟을 정한거냐?
That's right. Steal the Linear Motor Car.
그렇다, 리니아 모타카를 훔치는 거다
Linear Motor Car?
리니아 모타카?
This!
이거다!
The Linear Motor Car is able to reach a top speed of 500km/h.
리니아 모타카는 시속 500Km
It is the fastest maglev train in the world and has no wheels.
스피드는 세계 제일
The first-run ceremony for the Linear Motor Car will be tomorrow morning, departing from Tokyo Station.
이 도쿄 상공을 달리게 될 리니아 모타카는
So, this is it?
음 저건가
Finally we got some work to do! I'm all fired up!
드디어 일이다, 불타오르는군!
I'm burning! I'm burning!
타고 있다, 탄다구!
That's right! Burn!
그래, 불타는 거다!
Stop, you idiot!
에잇, 그만해, 자식들아!
So, you're a member of the cosmic police?
그러면 엑스카이저는 우주 경찰이야?
Yes, that's right.
그래, 그렇게 된거다
My friends and I are know as the Kaisers.
동료들은 나를 카이저스라고 부르고 있지
The Kaisers...
카이저스?
The one that took on that dinosaur's form is a space pirate known as Geister.
그 공룡모형 안에 들어가 있던 건 우주 해적 가이스터였다
Space pirate?
우주해적?
His boss is Dino Geist, the worst villain in the whole universe.
두목은 다이노 가이스터라고 불리는 우주 최악의 대악당이다
They destroy the peace like a rampaging storm, stealing treasure with his gang.
그들은 평화파괴와 모든 보물약탈을 즐기는 무리로 우주에 폭풍을 일으키고 있다
Now they've targeted the Earth.
이번에는 지구에 나타났다
That's why I've got a favor to ask you, Kouta.
그런데 코우타, 네게 부탁이 있다
Should you ever come across any information regarding their movement, let me know immediately.
만약 네게 녀석들의 정보가 들어오면 나에게 즉시 알려주길 바란다
I just came to Earth, and don't know much about it.
난 이제 막 도착해서 지구에 대해서는 아직 아는 게 없다
I haven't a clue about what would they go after.
녀석들이 뭘 노릴지 모른다
Your help would be most appreciated.
네 도움이 필요하다
I got it! If I come across anything, I'll let you know right away!
알았어, 무슨 일이 있으면 바로 알려주면 되는 거지?
That's good.
그래
Also, you promised to keep my existence a secret, so I hope you'll keep your word.
그리고 나에 대해서는 비밀로 하기로 한 약속은 반드시 지켜주길 바란다
Right!
응!
Should my identity become known, the adults would cause a ruckus.
내 정체가 밝혀지면 분명 어른들은 크게 떠들어 댈테고
It might affect all of mankind, and we don't want that to happen.
지구의 문명에 영향을 미치게 되고.. 우린 그렇게 되길 바라지 않는다
Right, I understand.
응, 알았어
It's almost as if I'm a member of the cosmic police myself!
왠지 우주경찰의 일원이 된 기분인데!
Good morning, Kouta-kun.
코우타, 안녕!
Mr. Tokuda, don't scare me like that!
토쿠다 아저씨..깜짝 놀랬잖아요!
What are you doing here dressed like that?
너 그 옷차림으로 뭐하고 있었냐?
You should know that I'm now a member of the cosmic police!
제가 우주 경찰의 일원이 됐거든요
What's this "cosmic police"?
뭔 소리냐, 우주경찰이라니?
Nothing! It's a secret! Please forget about what I said!
취소, 취소! 지금 말은 못들은 걸로 해주세요
Anyway, you're here this early because you got another scoop, right?
그런데 이렇게 이른 아침부터 오신 걸보니 역시 특종이라도 건지셨나 보죠?
Nope, not at all! I came to pick up the chief and his wife.
아니, 그게 아니고 오늘은 편집장님과 사모님을 마중온거야
Isn't today Sunday? Isn't it papa's day off?
오늘 일요일잖아요 아빠 쉬시는 날 아닌가요?
Huh? You mean you don't know?
어, 너 못들었냐?
It's this! "Linear Motor Car: Ltd. Exp. to Dream"
이거야, 이거! 꿈의 초특급 리니아.모타카
This is... the Linear Motor Car?
이건...리니아 모타카잖아요?
Your parents are going on a trip on the first train!
너희 부모님이 이걸 타실 거거든
Of course, I'm going, too!
물론 나도 탈거다~
What!?
에~!
Why didn't you tell me!?
어째서 말 안했었냐구요!
Mama... didn't you tell Kouta about today?
여보, 코우타에게 오늘 여행얘기 안했어?
Oh my, didn't I?
어머, 말 안했나?
Come on, take me too!
아~ 나도 데려가줘요~
I would like to take you along, but only two of us are invited for today.
데려가고 싶은 마음이야 굴뚝같지만 오늘은 엄마 아빠만 초대받았단다
Maybe next time.
오늘은 그냥 넘어가자
Chief, I think you've packed too much!
편집장님, 짐을 너무 많이 싸셨잖아요
Mama, don't you think you've gone overboard?
여보, 좀 많은 거 아냐?
You think?
글쎄요..그런가요?
What did you put in?
뭘 넣으셨는데요?
Meat, onion, potato, carrot, and pepper...
고기랑, 양파랑, 감자랑, 당근이랑,후춧가루..
Huh?
앙?
Oh my, did I forget the salt?
어머~소금을 깜박했네~
Good morning! What are you guys doing so early?
안녕히 주무셨어요? 아침부터 무슨일로 난리법석이예요?
Sister! Did you know that mama and papa are going on the Linear Motor Car today?
누나! 누나는 오늘 엄마 아빠가 리니아 모타카에 타는 거 알고 있었어?
I knew.
알고 있었지
Then I was the only one!
그럼 나만...
Mama, what are you making?
엄마 뭐 만들어요?
Curry! It should be ready in about two hours.
카레~ 이제 두 시간만 끓이면 먹을 수 있어
Two hours!? Mama, what about your trip?
두 시간이라니? 엄마 여행은 갈거예요 말거예요?
Oh! Oh right!
아 그래! 그게 있었지!
Geez...
이렇다니까!
Leave the rest to Kouta and me. You should get ready to leave.
이제부터는 코우타랑 내가 할테니까 엄마는 갈 준비나 하세요
Well, we're all set! Should we get going?
그럼, 준비는 다 됐군요 출발하시죠!
You're coming too, Mr. Tokuda?
어머, 토쿠다씨도 동행하시나요?
That's right!
예, 그렇습니다
I'm going to be writing an article on the Linear Motor Car.
전 리니아 모타카 취재차 동행하게 됐습니다
What about me...?
나도...
Is that so...? I've been waiting so long to go on a trip with just the two of us...
그렇군요...몇 년만에 해보는 부부 여행이라고 생각하고 있었는데...
It's alright, mama. We'll let him take our bags for us.
그냥 좋은 쪽으로 생각해, 여보 이 사람도 짐꾼으로는 쓸 수 있거든
What about me...?
저기, 나도..
-I guess so! -Thank you very much!
그러면 되겠군요 -감사합니다
-Understand? You better get that article done! -Yes, sir!
알겠지? 자네 취재 제대로 해야 하네! -예!
I... I... I want to go too.
나..나..나도 타고 싶어요
Take care of that lunch.
집단속 잘 해라 お留守番(るすばん)-집지키기
I said I will! Don't worry and have a nice trip!
알았다니까요! 걱정말고 여유있게 놀다오세요!
Bye!
다녀오마!
Don't forget to get me a souvenir!
선물사오는 거 잊으면 안돼요!
Well, now, I promised my friends I'd go out with them.
그럼, 난 이제부터 친구랑 약속 있어서 나갈거거든
Eh!?
에?
Take care of the curry! It'll stick on the pot if you don't stir it occasionally.
카레 만들어 놔~ 눌러붙지 않게 냄비 잘 들여다 보고!
What's up with that!?
뭐 하자는 거야!
Two hours should be enough for curry to be finished, so it shouldn't be too hard!
두 시간 정도면 카레도 익을테니까 일도 아니지 뭐!
See ya!
난 간다!
W- wait a sec!
자...잠깐 거기 서!
Thanks!
부탁해~
What the heck! You're so selfish!
뭐야, 자기 맘대로 나가고!
I wanna ride on the Linear Motor Car...
아~ 리니아 모타카 타고 싶다~
Linear Motor Car?
리니아 모타카?
Mario! Mario!
마리오! 마리오!
What is a Linear Motor Car?
리니아 모타카가 뭐지?
That's right... you can't speak the human language.
그렇군.. 넌 인간의 말을 할 줄 모르는군 君は人間の言葉は?れなかったんだな
Why did you come here!?
자넨 여기 뭐 하러 온건가?
Oh, that's right!
아! 그렇지! 알았습니다
Treasure, treasure... where could be that Linear Motor Car be?
보물이라..보물... 리니아 모타카는 어디 있는거야?
Chief! It's finally time!
편집장님, 드디어 탔습니다
Ah! that's right! I forgot!
아! 그렇지,잊을 뻔 했구만
Where are you going!?
어이, 어디 가나?
Lunch box! I'll go get some lunch boxes!
아 예! 도시락말입니다, 도시락!
Well, it's the moment we've all been waiting for...
자, 드디어 금세기 가장 기대되는 이벤트입니다
The Linear Motor Car is going on its first departure.
리니아 모타카가 이제 곧 출발하려 하고 있습니다
Once more our country will take a step forward on train manufacturing into history.
세계적으로 자랑할 만한 우리나라의 철도기술이 한 보 더 나아가
Well, that's just great.
쳇...할 수 없지 뭐...
Crap!
큰 일이다!
Safe!
safe~
A dime!
시..십엔!
Oh no!
망했다!
It's finally time for the world's fastest, the Linear Motor Car, to depart!
자 드디어 세계최고속의 리니아 모타카가 출발합니다
What is that Tokuda doing...
토쿠다 도대체 뭐하고 있는 건지..
Oh my! Over there!
어머, 저기에...
That idiot!
당체 원!
Well, now we can finally be alone, right, dear?
이걸로 우리끼리의 여행이 됐네요,여보
It left...
가버렸다!
Look at that elegance! The speeding bullet!
저 모습을 보십시오! 그야말로 달리는 탄환입니다
The express of dreams!
꿈의 초특급열차입니다
Tch! Must be boring!
쳇, 재미없겠구만 뭐!
How will I manage to finish all these three lunch boxes on my own...
혼자서 어떻게 도시락 세 개를 먹냐~
W- what the-!?
뭐..뭐래?
What in the world!? A monster just appeared in Tokyo Station!
믿을 수 없는 일입니다 도쿄역에 괴물이!
Ahhhh! It's a Geister!
아~우주해적 가이스터야!
Looks like it took off already. Shit!
벌써 출발 한건가! 젠장! 翼龍型のプテラガイスト 익룡형-프테라가이스터
Kouta, tell me the location.
코우타, 장소를 알려다오
Right.
응
Here!
여기야
Understood. Hang on tight!
알았다, 잘 잡고 있어야 한다
Got it.
응
The Pteranodon robot took off right after it attacked.
덮쳤던 익룡같은 로봇은 날아가 버렸대!
There's a treasure around here, right?
이 곳에 너희들이 보물이라 할 만한 것이 있나?
A treasure?
우리들의 보물?
That's right! The Linear Motor Car departed from here today!
아! 그러고보니 리나아 모타카가 여기서 출발하긴 했는데...
That's it!
그거다!
That's what they're after!
녀석들은 그 걸 노리는 게 분명하다
This is Exkaiser. Blue Raker, Green Raker, do you copy?
여기는 엑스카이저! 블루레이커, 그린레이커! 들리나?
This is Blue Raker. I read you loud and clear.
여기는 블루레이카, 잘 들린다 ブル-レイカ-靑い新幹線
This is Green Raker. I also copy.
여기는 그린레이카! 이 쪽도 잘 들린다 グリ-ンレイカ-綠の新幹線
Did something happen, Exkaiser?
무슨 일이 생겼나, 엑스카이저?
The Geisters are on the move. Requesting backup.
가이스터가 활동을 시작했다 지원을 부탁한다
Understood. We're on our way.
알았다 즉시 지원하러 가겠다 아우야, 드디어 일이다 ブル-レイカ- 菊池正美 키쿠치 마사미
-Drop off your passengers and move out! -Got it, brother!
-손님들이 내리면 바로 급히 와라 -알았습니다, 형님! グリ-ンレイカ- 草尾毅 쿠사오 타케시
Who are Blue Raker and Green Raker?
블루 레이커하고 그린 레이커라니 누구야?
They're also Kaisers.
카이저스의 동료다
Eh? Your friends are coming?
에~ 동료가 있었어?
They're twin brothers.
그들은 쌍동이 형제다
Twins?
쌍동이?
Is it good?
맛있어요?
It is!
맛있어요~
Armor Geist! Did you bring my invention?
아마가이스터! 내가 만든 건 가지고 왔나?
You mean this?
이거지? 암모사우루스(Ammosaurus) 뜻:모래 도마뱀, 뒷다리로 걷거나 네발로 걷기도
Please hurry! I have to let the chief know about what happened at Tokyo Station.
서둘러요, 편집장님께 도쿄역의 사건을 알려드려야 하니까!
Why are there Shinkansens running through here...?
어째서 이런데를 신칸선이 달리는 거지? 何でこんなところを新幹線が走ってるんだ?
It really is fast. I barely have the time to see the scenery.
정말 빠르네요..경치 구경할 틈도 없네요
I'm perfectly happy if the only scenery I see is you.
경치구경보다 난 당신만 있으면 행복해
Oh, papa!
당신도 참~
Huh? How strange... is there really a station around here?
이상하네? 이런 곳에 정차역이 있었나?
I can finally look at the scenery.
이젠 풍경이 보이네요
Well? I'm a genius!
어떠냐, 내 솜씨가!
That's something you'd be proud of.
제법 자랑할 만한 물건을 만들었구만 劍龍型のア-マ-ガイスト 검용형 암모가이스터
Ah! The railway bridge! Exkaiser, do something!
아! 철교가! 엑스카이저, 도와줘!
Papa and mama are riding in that Linear Motor Car!
저 리니아 모타카 안에 엄마하고 아빠가 타고 계신다구
I understand. You wait here, Kouta.
알고 있다 코우타 넌 잠시 여기서 기다리고 있어라
Here...? Where?
여기라니..어디?
Huh? How did that happen?
뭐야! 어떻게 된거지?
Change, Exkaiser!
Change! Exkaiser ! チェ-ンジ! エクスカイザ ! 체인지! 엑스카이저 !
You're Exkaiser!
넌 엑스카이저!
Ptera Geist and Armor Geist, right?
프테라 가이스터와 아마가이스터로군
Geisters, you scoundrels!
가이스터 악당놈들! ガイスタ-の惡黨共め!
I won't allow you to practice your evil ways on Earth!
이 지구에서 악행을 저지르는 건 내가 용서하지 못한다 この地球で惡事を勤くことは私が許さん！
What did you say?
뭐야?
Pig-headed flatfoot... Eat this!
그렇게 나온다면..받아라! プテラガイスト 小杉十郞太:코스기 쥬로타 프테라노돈-백악기의 익룡
Get him! Destroy him!
해치워! 녀석을 두둘겨 뭉개버려! ア-マ-ガイスト 西村知道 니시무라 토모미치
Darling! I think this bridge is moving!
여보, 왠지 움직이는 거 같지 않아요? 이 다리요 -그래...
Wow! It's a robot!
굉장해...로봇이잖아!
That's it! Crush him!
그렇지! 저대로 봉인해 버리자!
-Let's go, little brother! -Right!
-가자, 아우야! -예!
Change, Blue Raker!
Change! Blue Raker!
Change, Green Raker!
Change! Green Raker!
Raker Brothers!
Raker Brothers! レイカ-ブラザ-ズ 레이커 브라더스!
Darling! This bridge really is moving!
여보, 역시 움직이는 것 같아요 이 다리...!
Y- yeah...
그..그렇군
Exkaiser, are you alright?
엑스카이저 괜찮아?
Yes. Blue Raker, Green Raker, you take care of them.
아! 블루 레이커, 그린 레이커! 너희들은 녀석들을 맡아줘
-I will save the Linear Motor Car. -Got it!
나는 리니아 모타카를 구조하겠다 -알았다!
-Green Raker, let's catch them! -Right, brother!
그린 레이커, 녀석들을 꼼작 못하게 하자! -알았어요 형님!
-They got a lot of nerve... Let's go, Armor Geist! -Right!
건방진 것들! 가자, 암모 가이스터! -음!
Bind Crash!
Bind crash バインドクラッシュ 바인드 크러쉬!
Spike Cutter!
Spike cutter! スパイクカッタ-! 스파이크 커터!
Oh no! The Linear Motor Car is gonna fall off the bridge!
큰일났다! 리니아 모타카가 철교에서 떨어지겠어!
King Loader!
King Loader キング-ロ-ダ- 킹 로더!
Form Up!
Form Up! フォ-ムオブ! 폼 업!
Giant Fusion, King Exkaiser!
Huge union King Exkaiser 巨大合體 キングエクスカイザ 거대합체 킹엑스카이저! Height：32.9m/Weight：177t 주행속도250.4km/h/점프력1200.8m
Exkaiser got bigger!
엑스 카이저가 커졌어
Oh no! Green Raker, let's combine!
안되겠다, 그린 레이커 합체하자!
Alright, let's go!
좋아, 가자!
Form Up!
Form Up! フォ-ムオブ! 폼 업!
Left&Right Fusion, Ultra Raker!
좌우합체 울트라 레이커! 左右合體ウルトラレイカ- Height：10.8m Weight：34.9t
Thanks, Ultra Raker!
고맙다, 울트라 레이커!
Kaiser Sword!
Kaiser Sword カイザ-ソド 카이저 소드!
Kaiser Flame!
Kaiser Frame カイザ-フレ-ム! 카이저 프레임!
Thunder Flash!
Thunder Flash! サンダ-フラッシュ! 썬더 플래쉬!
Alright! Awesome!
해치웠다 굉장해!
Crap, we failed! Run!
일이 안풀리는군! 실패다!
Hey! W-wait! Hey!
어이, 기다려! 야!
Idiot!
이 못난 사람아!
You lost the scoop because of a lunch box! You won't be getting any lunch at all if you keep doing like that!
도시락 때문에 특종을 놓치다니 그러고도 신문기자로 밥먹고 살겠나?
I'm sorry!
면목없습니다
And what exactly were you doing until now!?
대체 이제야 나타나다니!
But that sure was awesome... you beat that big guy in one hit!
정말 굉장했어 그렇게 덩치큰 적을 한방에 날렸잖아!
Yes, and our job is done. We should hurry back home.
그래, 일을 마쳤으니 서둘러 돌아가자
Your sister should be waiting, right?
너희 누나가 기다리고 있겠구나
Ah! The stove! I forgot to turn it off!
아! 가스불 끄는 거 까먹었다
Oh no!
망했다~
What the hell were you doing? If I hadn't come home, this could have started a fire!
너 도대체 뭐 하고 있었어! 내가 안왔으면 불 날 판이었잖아!
Sorry...
미안해..
No excuses.
미안으로 끝날 일이니?
Where in the world were you playing anyway?
지금까지 어디서 놀고 온거야?
Take a good look!
잘 보란 말야!
The pot is all burnt! We can't eat this!
냄비가 타버렸잖아! 이 걸 어떻게 먹냐구!
It's too bad you're getting yelled at, Kouta.
불쌍하군... 혼나는 모양인데...코우타..
Faraway wind carries your dream
遙かな 風が 夢を 運んで 아득한 바람이 꿈을 가져와
What could you discover from this excited feeling
ときめく 事に 何を 見つけるの 설레이는 일에서 무엇을 찾아낼까
Dreams get bigger strongly and fast
强く 早く ふくらむ 夢に 강하고 빠르게 부풀어 오르는 꿈에
Don't forget to be who you are
自分らしさ 忘れずに 자신다운 모습을 잊지 말고
Embrace your enthusiastic heart
夢中に なれる 心 抱きしめ 정열적인 마음 꼭 껴안고
And try walking that path
その 道を 步いてみてね 그 길을 걸어가 보는거야
Big problem!
大變だ！
All the electricity in my city is stolen!
ボクの町の電氣が全部盜まれちゃった！
It's pitch black at night, the trains have stopped, and I can't even watch TV!
夜は眞っ暗だし,電車は止まっちゃうし
I bet the Geisters are behind this.
きっとまたガイスタ-のしわざだ！
Exkaiser! Call together all the Kaisers and return our electricity!
エクスカイザ-！
On the next episode of Brave Exkaiser,
次回,勇者エクスカイザ-『大停電で大こんらん』
Is there an alien in your home, too?
君んちにも宇宙人、いる？ 第３話　大停電で大こんらん